

Soumyajeet Das

Jr. Software Engineer

About Me

Computer science graduate with 2+ years of experience as a MERN Stack Developer at Cognizant. During this journey of 2+ years, I served as Analyst Trainee and Junior Software Engineer in Cognizant. Believes in continuous self-development.

My Contact

soumyajeetdas@outlook.com



+91 7044139099



Kolkata



https://soumyajeetportfolio.netlify.app/



in linkedin.com/in/soumyajeetdas19

Hard Skill

- HTML
- Javascript
- React JS
- Node JS
- Express JS
- Redux
- · Redux Toolkit
- · React Bootstrap
- Bootstrap 5
- Mongo DB
- SQL Server
- REST API
- JSON
- POSTMAN
- Azure Applnsight
- Azure Devops
- GitHub

Soft Skill

- Observation
- Communication

Professional Experience



COGNIZANT | Jr. Software Engineer

Alaska Airlines 07/2022 - Present

Key responsibilities:

- Collaborated with the team to migrate outdated applications to newer technologies using MERN Stack, increasing efficiency and load time of applications by 90%.
- · Implemented a cron job using Node.js to email reports to users, which saved 70+ hours of manual work.
- · Managed Team in absence of Team Lead.



COGNIZANT | Programmer Analyst Trainee

Alaska Airlines 07/2021 - 07/2022

Key responsibilities:

- Developed a web application using MERN Stack for the support team to store support documents and related datas, reducing the support team's effort by 70%.
- · Contributed actively to the analysis of errors by debugging and performed troubleshooting with SME's when there were issues at the production level..
- · Have acquired the art of communicating efficiently and professionally with clients and vendors in order to meet their needs
- Guiding the Team with the knowledge of MERN Stack.



COGNIZANT | INTERNSHIP

04/2021 - 07/2021

Key responsibilities:

- Successfully completed MERN Stack Training by securing 95%
- Achieved hands-on experience by creating personal projects under the guidance of mentors.

Education Background



Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology

B.Tech in Computer Science, Bhubaneshwar GPA - 8.87 07/2017 - 07/2021



Higher Secondary (CBSE)

Kalyani Central Model School, Kolkata Aggregate - 86% 04/2014 - 04/2016



Secondary(ICSE)

Nopany High , Kolkata Aggregate - 85.2% 04/2004 - 04/2014

Languages

English

Proficient



Hindi

Proficient



Bengali Native



Personal Projects

The Bengalis

10/2022 - Present

Description:

- A Food Ordering Web App created with MERN Stack and Redux library.
- It is a fully responsive website with a cart system, user profile section(can upload profile images), payment Gateway using Paypal and user authentication using JWT Token.
- The frontend is created with React JS, React Router v6, Redux Toolkit and React Bootstrap.
- The backend is created with Node JS and Express JS.
- Used Mongo DB as Database.
- Frontend is hosted in Netlify and backend is hosted in Vercel.
- Future Scope will be adding social media authentication and authorization.
- GitHub Link: https://github.com/SoumyajeetDas/Food-Order-React
- Website Link: https://bengali-food-webapp.netlify.app/

Cryptos

12/2022 - Present

Description:

- A Web App for getting live market information on the Crypto
- The front end is created with React JS and Material UI 5.
- Consumed Coin Geko API to get the Crypto Coin Data.
- · Authentication and Authorization using Google Auth with the help
- It is a fully responsive website hosted in Netlify.
- GitHub Link: https://github.com/SoumyajeetDas/Crypto- MaterialUI-Project
- Website Link: https://cryptocurrency-webapp.netlify.app/

Certificates



Front-End Web Development with React

Coursera

11/2022 - Ongoing



Server-side Development with NodeJS, Express and **MongoDB**

Coursera 11/2022 - Ongoing



Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Microsoft

03/2022 - Ongoing